{"test_questions": [[{"question": "The bacteria which is novobiocin resistant is", "opta": "Staphylococcus aureus", "optb": "S epidermidis", "optc": "S saprophyticus", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The bacteria which are inhibited on crystal violet (1:500,000) blood agar, is/are", "opta": "Streptococci", "optb": "Staphylococci", "optc": "Both (a) and (b)", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following Staphylococcal haemolysins does not possess leucocidal activity?", "opta": "\u03b1 haemolysin", "optb": "\u03b3 haemolysin", "optc": "\u03b2 haemolysin", "optd": "\u03b4 haemolysin", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The genus/genera that belongs to the family Micrococcaceae is", "opta": "Micrococcus", "optb": "Staphylococcus", "optc": "Planococcus", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Identify the bacteria which is oxidase-negative and catalase-positive?", "opta": "Staphylococcus", "optb": "Streptococcus", "optc": "Neisseria", "optd": "Pseudomonas", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Coagulase-reacting factor is necessary for", "opta": "slide coagulase test", "optb": "tube coagulase test", "optc": "precipitation test", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Bacteria which produces coagulase is", "opta": "S epidermidis", "optb": "S saprophyticus", "optc": "S aureus", "optd": "S hominis", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Staphylococcal food poisoning usually manifests itself following ingestion of contaminated food after", "opta": "2-6 hours", "optb": "8-12 hours", "optc": "12-18 hours", "optd": "18-36 hours", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following Staphylococcal haemolysins does not cause lysis of human RBCs?", "opta": "\u03b2 haemolysin", "optb": "\u03b3 haemolysin", "optc": "\u03b1 haemolysin", "optd": "\u03b4 haemolysin", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The toxin of Staphylococcus aureus that may result into scalded skin syndrome is", "opta": "Enterotoxin", "optb": "Leucocidin", "optc": "Epidermolytic toxin", "optd": "Haemolysin", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The bacteria which can ferment mannitol anaerobically is", "opta": "Staphylococcus aureus", "optb": "S epidermidis", "optc": "S saprophyticus", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Protein A is found in cell wall of", "opta": "coagulase-negative staphylococci", "optb": "Staphylococcus aureus", "optc": "Micrococci", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The most common cause of cystitis (after Escherichia coli) in healthy sexually active women is", "opta": "Staphylococcus saprophyticus", "optb": "Proteus mirabilis", "optc": "Pseudomonas aeruginosa", "optd": "Klebsiella pneumoniae", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following can be used to detect clumping factor?", "opta": "tube coagulase test", "optb": "slide coagulase test", "optc": "precipitation test", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Most strains of Staphylococcus aureus indicate", "opta": "phosphatase production", "optb": "a golden-yellow pigment", "optc": "\u03b2-haemolysis on sheep blood agar", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}